Kris Chandler

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Certified professional in Customer Service (CSR) with 10+ years of experience in sales and production management, implementing proven functional tactics that supports the business plan of the organization. Currently responsible for (but not limited to) adding value to the Value Chain Strategy (VCS), as well as successfully conceptualizing and implementing new competitive advantage methodologies which strengthened the organizations strategic business plan.

EXPERIENCE

Customer Service Associate, Lowes, Woodlands, Texas- October 2016- Present

Provide customer service to customers. Other job responsibilities include:

- Achieved and surpassed monthly sales goals of appliances and outdoor power equipment sales
- Development and execution of outdoor reconstruction projects
- Down stocking products, maintaining a clean, stocked department and operate forklift

Operations Manager, Dow Machine Corp., Houston, Texas – February 2010 – December 2015

Provide production analysis and project management for President of operations. Conducted logistics for all completed and received projects. Other responsibilities and achievements include:

- Co-Authored safety policies to OSHA standards while sitting on the company's safety committee.
- Created and implemented business plans achieving or passing quarterly goals set by President of operations using strategic tools (SWOT analysis, Balanced scorecard, RBV, or PEST analysis).
- Increased profits while cutting cost using cost-benefit analysis techniques resulting in value adding to the company's bottom line.
- Improved logistics department through precise organizational strategies
- Successfully developed employees by creating actions plans which encouraged continuous improvement reducing turnover for the organization

Sales Manager, Planet Ford, Spring, Texas – August 2007 – February 2010

Served as the direct point of contact for Planet Ford, increasing sales and contributing to top ranked Ford dealership in region. Responsibilities included:

- Achieved favorable outcomes deploying negotiation techniques through product differentiation
- Tracked sales data and increased repeat customers using a CRM software
- Reached sales and personal goals with the use of cognitive skills and tacit knowledge exemplifying competitive differentiation among peers.

Operations Generalist, Cinemark, The Woodlands, Texas – April 2001 – August 2007

Performed cross functional duties and served as team leader for each department reporting to department managers and assistant managers for Cinemark. Responsibilities included:

- Excelled as a cross functional Customer Service Representative for organization involving critical and creative thinking skills to solve issues.
- Conducted inventory counts and cut waste of products by implementing innovative stocking techniques.
- Prosperous team leader with a high rate of meeting sales projections set by upper management through effective communication and collaboration with team members.

EDUCATION

- University of Phoenix; Texas BS, Business Management 2017
- San Angelo State, 2004 2005
- Blinn College, 2002 2004